NISHAT ANJUM

□+8801723124778 | Image: Imag

Summary_

Principal Software Engineer with a decade of impressive background in designing and developing enterprise-level software solutions. My expertise lies in JAVA and JVM-based technology stacks, software design patterns, and development methodologies. After scrutinizing my passion, comprehensive work experience, and definitive ambition, I have decided to pursue a research route Master's Program in the field of Software Engineering, which I believe will lead me to a career as a Computer and Software Specialist in the future.

Education 2.

University of Dhaka Dhaka, Bangladesh

BSc. (Honours) in Computer Science and Engineering

2007 - 2011

- **CGPA:** 3.37/4.00 (3.40 in last two academic years)
- Merit Position: 14th out of 45 students
- Courses: Software Engineering, Data Structures and Algorithms, Computer Programming Language, Database Management System, Operating System, Computer Networks, Data Communication, Discrete Mathematics, Theory of Computation, Artificial Intelligence
- **IELTS**: Overall Band Score **7.5** [L-9, R-7.5, W-7, S-6.5]

Research Interests

Software Engineering, Empirical Software Engineering, Application of Machine Learning in Software Engineering, Database and knowledge-base systems, Data Mining, Data Visualization, Human Computer Interaction.

Academic Research_

Title: Throughput Maximization in Device to Device(D2D) Enabled Cellular Network

University Of Dhaka

Supervisor: Professor DR. MD. ABDUR RAZZAQUE

2012

In this work, We addressed the spectrum-sharing problem between cellular and underlaying D2D communication. Our main goal was
to maximize the throughput of the underlying 3G cellular network in non-orthogonal Resource-Sharing mode. We proposed a Scheduled
resource-sharing Algorithm for eNodeB that intelligently identified potential D2D connection pairs and optimally shared UpLink and DownLink resources by calculating SINR for each pair.

Technical Expertise_

Language: Java, Python, C/C++, JavaScript, TypeScript, R

Frameworks: Spring-[Boot, Security, MVC, Webflow, Data JPA, Batch, HATEOAS, GraphQL], Python Flask, Angular, Hibernate, JPA, Mockito

Web Services: REST, SOAP

Middlewares: WebLogic, WildFly, Tomcat, TomcatEE, Glassfish

Databases: MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, In-memory Data Structure Store-REDIS, Cloud Object Storage - MINIO

Tools: Maven, Gradle, Ant, Postman, Git, Bitbucket, Docker

OS Platforms: Linux, Windows, Mac

Big Data: Kafka, Apache KUDU, Apache Spark, Apache Druid, Elasticsearch

Work Experience_

Tiger IT Bangladesh Limited. 🗹

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Oct 2022 - present

- Principal Software Engineer
- Supervising and training a Development team of four software engineers.
- · Providing technical guidance to the team and overseeing the technical aspects of four Government projects and upcoming Projects.
- Improving the performance of existing software solutions.
- Investigating Project-related objections and taking necessary measurements to ensure optimal software performance.
- Regularly attend team meetings to discuss projects, brainstorm ideas, and propose solutions to any issues.
- Designing, coding, and debugging new projects.

Senior Software Engineer

Oct 2019 - Sept 2022

- Supervised a team of four software engineers to ascertain the successful completion of deliverables of **four country-scale projects**.
- Performed various RnD and provided expert support and guidance on architectural changes in ongoing initiatives taken by the company.
- · Continuously contributed to troubleshooting issues in production deployment and performance tuning.
- Reviewed code for defects and quality against technical documents and standard practices.
- Designing, coding, and debugging new projects

Software Engineer Dec 2015 - Sept 2019

- Extensively re-engineered legacy software system to improve scalability and increased performance by approximately 35%.
- · Core architect of a large-scale data migration project involving a highly complex process that successfully migrated approximately 120M Demographic and Biometric data within 42 hours.
- Developed High volume and low latency Restful APIs for various client applications serving **responses less than 30ms.**
- Developed data streaming pipeline using Apache Kafka that combine messaging and storage of both historical and real-time data.
- Developed a high-performance real-time fast data Analytics application using Apache Druid, Kudu, and Kafka.
- Designed and developed Report modules for multiple ongoing projects which involved complex query writing.
- Assisted the Junior Software Engineers in solving technical problems and mentored them in writing high-quality code.

Therap BD Ltd. 🗹 Dhaka, Bangladesh

Associate Software Engineer

Oct 2014 - Dec 2015

- Worked with Technical Staff to understand problems with software and correct them.
- Developed new features for the MAR module of The Therap application.
- Wrote a successful migration script incorporating ETL process to store lookup standard diagnosis codes (e.g. ICD-9/10).
- Solved user reported bugs of different modules in the Therap Application.
- · Learning and experimenting the usability of various technologies in The Therap application.

Junior Software Engineer

Jan 2013 - Sept 2014

- · Learning, installing and reviewing various technologies related to software development.
- Investigated users reported bugs in the codebase and resolved them.
- Did code refactoring to increase readability and performance in different modules.

Industrial Projects 🗷

Bangladesh NID application System

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring MVC, Spring Security, JSP, Semactic-UI, JQuery]

· An online public portal where citizen of Bangladesh can apply for NID card and voter registration

Rohingya AFIS And AFRS adjudication System

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Python Flusk, Angular.js, Spring Boot, Ouartz Scheduler]

· An application which ceaselessly verifies new voter applications with Rohingya AFIS and AFRS database

CMS system for Election Commission Officials

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring Boot, Spring Security, JWT Token, JSP, Bootstrap, vue.js]

Web Application for bangladesh election commission officials to oversee voter registration and NID card applications

Bangladesh Citizen data Migration Project

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring Boot-Scheduling, JDBC, Apache Kafka, Redis]

 A data migration project to migration 120M voter demographic and biometric data to elasticsearch, Apache KUDU, Redis, Minio and Oracle database.

Nepal HSENP Registration System

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring MVC, Spring Security, JSP, Semactic UI, JQuery]

· A online public portal where Nepal Citizen can apply for high security embossed number plate for their Vehicles.

Nepal HSENP Application management System

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring MVC, Spring Security, Thymeleaf, Bootstrap, JQuery, Oracle database]

• A web application for nepal DOTM officials to supervise HSENP printing applications.

Nepal vehicle data migration project

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring-Batch, Spring-Jdbc, Oracle Database]

A data migration projects to migrate 35M vehicle data to Oracle database.

Bangladesh NTMC National Datahub Project

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring Boot, Spring Security, JWT Token, Apache Kafka, Redis, GraphQL]

An ETL project for bangladesh NTMC which accumulate Citizen data from multiple sources and make them accessible for

Vehicle Tracking System - Banngladesh NTMC

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Alient JAVA SDK, MQTT, Caffeine Cache, Spring Boot, Spring Scheduling]

· The application unceasingly accumulates vehicle movement information by interfacing with Alien RFID Reader

Therap Application Technology Stack: [Spring MVC, JSP, EJB, Hibernate JPA, Oracle Database] Therap BD Ltd.

- · Developed new feature in Medication Administration Record(MAR) module to record patient medication record
- Developed a migration project to store lookup standard ICD-9/10 diagnosis code into relational Database

Academic Projects_____

Buddy Circle-A Social networking web application

University Of Dhaka

Internet Programming

• An application developed back in 2012 using spring mvc, jsp, html5, jpa, mysql

Tic Tac Toe Game using ATmega32 microcontroller

University Of Dhaka

Computer Peripherals and Interfacing

2010

2012

A multiplayer tic-tac-toe game written in C language for ATmega32 Controller

Dots and Boxes - Online Multiplayer Game

Object Oriented Programming-JAVA

• An online multiplayer game developed using JAVA Applet and socket programming

Avoid collision Game

University Of Dhaka

Programming Language Fundamental- C Language

A simple single player game developed using C i-Graphics library

Unix Shell University Of Dhaka

Operating System
- A simple bash like Unix shell which executed linux command using exec().

Competition and Achievements _____

2018	Champion , Women Table Tennis Tournament arranged by TigerIT Bangladesh.	Dhaka, Bangladesh
2015	Runner-Up, Women Table Tennis Tournament arranged by Therap BD. Ltd.	Dhaka, Bangladesh
2011	University Stipend, Shamsunnahar Trust Scholarship	University of Dhaka
2007	Education Board Scholarship, HSC Board Exam	Rajshahi, Bangladesh
2005	Education Board Scholarship, SSC Board Exam	Rajshahi, Bangladesh

Interests_

Table Tennis Table Tennis is my favorite sport of all. I play table tennis with my colleagues every day at my workplace. **Workout** I am a fitness freak. Some of my favorite activities are western yoga, low-impact aerobics, and Zumba.

Cooking I love baking and Cooking. Baking my birthday cake gives me ultimate joy. I try out new recipes every weekend. **Traveling** I am an avid traveler. I travel around in my own country and abroad whenever I find a possible opportunity.

Music | Music | enjoy almost all types of music. However, primarily | love Soul, Country, Indi, pop, Psychedelic, OST, and K-Pop.

Languages_

English Professional proficiency
Bengali Native proficiency
Hindi Bilingual proficiency

University Of Dhaka

2008